<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A regulation for seamen wherein a method is humbly proposed : whereby their majesties fleet may at all times be speedily and effectually mann'd and the merchants be more readily and cheaper serv'd, without having their men at any time press'd or taken away ... / by John Perry, late captain of the Signet-Fireship, now a prisoner in the Marshalses ...</title>
            <author>Perry, John, 1670-1732.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1695</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 99 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 31 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A54459</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing P1649</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R30771</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">11467389</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 11467389</idno>
            <idno type="VID">47803</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A54459)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 47803)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1467:24)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A regulation for seamen wherein a method is humbly proposed : whereby their majesties fleet may at all times be speedily and effectually mann'd and the merchants be more readily and cheaper serv'd, without having their men at any time press'd or taken away ... / by John Perry, late captain of the Signet-Fireship, now a prisoner in the Marshalses ...</title>
                  <author>Perry, John, 1670-1732.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[10], 48 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1695.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Includes: "A short narrative of his case relating to his loss of the said ship ... "</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the University of Illinois (Urbana-Champaign Campus). Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England and Wales. --  Royal Navy --  Regulations --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>England and Wales. --  Royal Navy --  Pay, allowances, etc.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Defenses.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:47803:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:47803:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A REGULATION FOR SEAMEN WHEREIN A METHOD is humbly propoſed, WHEREBY Their MAJESTIES Fleet may at all times be ſpeedily and effectually Mann'd, and the <hi>Merchants</hi> be more readily and cheaper ſerv'd, without having their Men at any time preſs'd or taken away;</p>
            <p>Setting forth The great Advantages that will accrue thereby to the KING <hi>Merchant,</hi> and <hi>Subject</hi> in general, whereby theſe Iſlands will be more ſecure and happy, the Kings Revenue conſiderably be eas'd, Trade in general be quicken'd and encourag'd, and every indivi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dual Subject receive benefit thereby, in leſſening the Price of all Naval Commodities;</p>
            <p>Wherein is alſo propos'd, A Method or Nurſery for training up of Seamen to ſupply the Loſs and Decay of them in Time of War:</p>
            <p>AS ALSO, The giving hereby equal Liberty and Advantage to all Seamen, removing many Hardſhips that they now ſuffer under, and giving them many Encouragements that they do not now enjoy.</p>
            <p>By <hi>JOHN PERRY,</hi> late Captain of the <hi>Signet-Fireſhip,</hi> now a Priſoner in the <hi>Marſhalſes,</hi> according to the Sentence of a late Court-Marſhal.</p>
            <p>To which is added, A ſhort NARRATIVE of his Caſe relating to his Loſs of the ſaid Ship in Company of the <hi>Diamond-Friggat,</hi> in <hi>September</hi> 1693.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printed in the Year 169<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="authors_note">
            <pb facs="tcp:47803:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:47803:2"/>
            <p>THE miſerable and unhappy Circumſtances that I now lie under, upon occaſion of my late heavy Sentence, and the Senſe of my now ſuffering Reputation in the World, would be ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficient to damp all Thoughts of a Dedication, were I not alſo conſcious of my own ſlender and weak Abilities; but under all theſe Preſſures and Diſad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vantages I cannot look up, nor dare to have that Preſumption, as to affix the Names of any Perſons of Honour to the Offspring of ſo loſt and forſaken a Wretch, but ſhall think it a Favour, if any ſuch Perſons ſhall vouchſafe to look upon any thing that carries my unhappy Name in the Front; and if they ſhall have Patience to peruſe theſe fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing PROPOSALS, and ſhall afterwards have ſo much Charity as to read my CASE alſo, and ſhall then pleaſe to have this kind Thought for me, that howſoever unfortunate the Action mentioned therein was, <hi>That I would have done bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter in it if I could:</hi> This would be ſome Relief to me under my preſent Sufferings, until ſuch
<pb facs="tcp:47803:3"/>time as God and my King ſhall pleaſe to enable me, by giving me ſome other Opportunity, which I cannot wholly deſpair of, whereby I may give the World ſuch further Satisfaction, as to believe that it is really true, and that what I did then do, was to the utmoſt of my Power.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>John Perry.</signed>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Marſhalſea-Priſon,</hi> 
                  <date>Decemb. 18. 1694.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="preface">
            <pb facs="tcp:47803:3"/>
            <head>THE PREFACE.</head>
            <p>HOW great Advantages for Riches and Strength all States and Kingdoms have that abound in Shipping, needs no Rhetorick to expreſs; Examples there are enough in Hiſtory to convince us of the Truth of it, and of how many States and Nations in all Ages have raiſed themſelves thereby to great Power, and whilſt by their Care and good Conduct, they have incouraged their ſhipping, Glory and Renown has ſtill attended them: but whenever by their great Opulency, or truſting to their own Security, they grew Careleſs or Supine; ſome more Induſtrious Sate and Nation have always got the Advantage of them. That this ever was, and ever will be, the fate of the World is no queſtion, and that it is of great moment for our Nation at this time to conſider of it, is as undoubtedly true.</p>
            <p>The Glory and Safty of theſe Nations conſiſts in two Parts, one depending on the other, the one is in a good and regu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar application of our Power at home for the Defence and Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>curity of theſe Iſlands from the inſults of our Enemies, and the other is in the openneſs, freedom and extent of our Trade
<pb facs="tcp:47803:4"/>abroad: As to the nature and extent of our Foreign Trade, it is not my buſineſs, nor in my power to ſpeak of it, it hath been ſufficiently treated of by a Perſon of great Judgment and perſpicuity in thoſe Affairs. I ſhall only add my hearty Wiſhes for the publick Good, that if any of our Trade has been at any time loſt, we may uſe our beſt endeavours, not only to regain, but enlarge it, which will not only prove an Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor, but a Security to theſe Nations.</p>
            <p>My preſent purpoſe is only to offer my weak Endeavours, in humbly propoſing ſome Regulation for the better exerting of our Naval Power, and to remove ſome preſent heavy Op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſions.</p>
            <p>Neceſſity puts us often upon Induſtry, and 'tis the want of ſomething that ſtill whets our Invention; and whether there is not cauſe for it in our preſent Exigency of Affairs, let any Man conſider. We have been in a <hi>Long War</hi> with a <hi>Powerful</hi> and <hi>Subtil Enemy,</hi> who has been undermining the Peace of <hi>Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtendom</hi> for ſeveral years; and who by his Art and Cunning has been contriving how to erect his own <hi>Trophies</hi> upon the <hi>Ruine of his Neighbours.</hi> Could it ever have been thought that the <hi>French,</hi> who in the memory of this Age were ſo inconſiderable in their <hi>Shipping,</hi> could ſteal ſo ſoon and ſecretly into ſuch great Power, as to bid Defiance to ſo many Princes by Land, and at the ſame time to maintain a <hi>Powerful</hi> and <hi>Numerous Fleet</hi> by Sea, little inferiour to two of the greateſt in the whole World, to dare us both when united in our own Channel? when it was before thought that the ſingle Force of either would have been ſufficient to have ſhut them up in their Ports, and have ruined them by Sea at any time. Thus we have thought, and thus have we been deceived; and tho (God be thanked) the Scale is now turned, yet however the Remem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brance
<pb facs="tcp:47803:4"/>of it cannot but be uſeful to us; to keep us waking for the future, that we may not ſleep too long in our own ſecurity, without providing or looking for future Emergencies, and that we may not ſuffer by any greater Power or ſudden Surprize of our Enemies, when we may not have an Ally to help us. And one true way to direct us how to provide for our Security, is, to look about us and ſee if any of our Nighbours are not better provided, and have better Methods than our ſelves; and if ſo, it will be abſolutely neceſſary that we ſhould amend ours, and think it no trouble to change our old Methods for better: for this is moſt certain, that if we are not as careful and industri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous, and take as good Methods as our Neighbours, however we may flatter our ſelves with Futurities, and put off our thoughts for providing againſt them; yet a time maycome when we ſhall feel the miſery of our Inadvertancies, as many Nations have done before us. I ſhall only trouble the Reader with one Paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſage, which I hope will not be thought impertinent. When I was an unfortunate Priſoner at <hi>St. Maloes,</hi> talking with a <hi>French Officer</hi> there, upon what might be the Iſſues and Events of this War; he was telling me, that however powerful we pretended to be at Sea, yet his <hi>Maſter would match us,</hi> and that had his <hi>Maſtor</hi> but the ſingle Trade of <hi>England</hi> or <hi>Holland,</hi> he would ſoon <hi>Ruine us both,</hi> by the method and order he obſerves in all his <hi>Maritime Affairs</hi> (all Seamen there being obliged at the King's immediate command to go on board his Fleet); as for <hi>Ships of War,</hi> ſays he, where there is Money to be had, they may be ſoon built and Stores provided; but the chief thing is the ready <hi>Manning</hi> and <hi>fitting them out,</hi> wherein, continues he, <hi>France</hi> has the Advantage: for, ſays he, your Ships are mann'd when the Seamen pleaſe, but ours when the King pleaſes. I could not but think his Argument had too much truth in it, and that if <hi>France</hi> had but the <hi>Numbers</hi> and <hi>Nurſeries of Seamen</hi> as we have, we ſhould ſoon find the ſmart of it.
<pb facs="tcp:47803:5"/>This I muſt confeſs, out of Natural Love to my Country, put me upon thoughts if ſome way could not be found out whereby we might ballance <hi>his Abſolute Power in Manning his Fleet:</hi> and whilſt I continued at <hi>St. Maloes</hi> I did apply my ſelf to it, and imogined that there could be no Expedient for it, except it could be ſo ordered, that they ſhould all paſs through the Fleet into <hi>Merchant-men;</hi> for which purpoſe I drew up the Scheme of a Project for it, much to the purpoſe as hereafter, and ſoon after my coming over, I gave a Draught of it to a Perſon of Honor, and of great Judgment, then an Admiral in the Fleet; only in that Copy I propoſed the Seamen to paſs thro' the Fleet, and in this through a Regiſter, which I have ſince thought to be more convenient. But ſince I have delivered ſome Copies of it out, ſome Reflections have been made as if I had taken my meaſures from Capt. <hi>St. Loe;</hi> and as it now cometh in my way I cannot but take notice of it, and ſolemnly proteſt my Ignorance of it, and that I never ſaw nor heard of any of his Propoſals till af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter I had delivered mine in to the Admiralty Board; and I hope it may the more eaſily be believed, ſeeing the great difference there is between his and mine, excepting the <hi>Regiſter,</hi> which, as I have lately been informed, not only Capt. <hi>St. Loe,</hi> but ſeveral other Perſons have formerly been upon. I beg pardon for this Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>greſſion, and return to ſhew what is the Deſign of theſe follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Papers.</p>
            <p>The Charge, Trouble, and Confuſion that we have been at all this War, to fit out and man our Fleet, is known to have been very great, and there has been many Grievances and Complaints that have on all ſides attended it; the Royal Navy always want<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Men on the one hand, and the Merchants being always ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liged to ſubmit to the extravagant Demands of Seamen on the other; one third part of our Seamen being generally ſuppoſed to lie hid on ſhear, in hope to make their Advantage in a Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chant
<pb facs="tcp:47803:5"/>Man, which, were there any Method to prevent, there would be no ſcarcity of Seamen, but enough to ſerve both: where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by the King's Fleet might always be mann'd, and the Merchants have them upon reaſonable Terms. For this reaſon have I been encouraged to offer my humble Endeavours, howſoever accepted, for the publick Good, not being ſo vain as to think, but that there may be many Errors and Imperfections in them, which were I not ignorant of. I would endeavour to correct or amend, but as it is, I must ſubmit them to the Judgments and Cenſures of more knowing Perſons, only hoping for this Favour, that if I ſhall be thought not fit for any Encouragement, they will at leaſt have this kind Thought for me, <hi>That I am willing to do all the good I can.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The following Popoſals have two Intentions, the firſt is in re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpect to the Safety, Honor and Defence of theſe Nations, whereby the King's Fleet may at any time, without Preſſing, be ſpeedily and effectually Mann'd without the great charge that the King is at in impreſſing Seamen, as late publickly repreſented by a very In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>genuous and Judicious Perſon, to amount to upwards of <hi>36000 l. per Ann.</hi> and theſe following Papers do not only propoſe how we may readily unite our <hi>Naval Strength,</hi> but give us alſo a true Inſpection and Knowledge of it, whereby our Numbers of Seamen may at all times be known, which is as neceſſary as to know the Number of our Ships; and if at any time their Numbers de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cline, or are not ſufficient to anſwer our preſent Neceſſities or Future Emergencies; that then, without groping in the dark, we may be able to provide for ſuch Recruits as will ſupply ſuch Defects: to which end I have alſo propoſed a Method as a Nurſery for Seamen, and that ſome ſuch Method ought to be taken, is moſt undoubtedly true.</p>
            <p>
               <pb facs="tcp:47803:6"/>The ſecond Intention of theſe Propoſals, is the fixing of Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chants Wages to a reaſonable Rate, and to relieve them from that great Oppreſſion that they and the whole Nation now ſuffer under, by the exorbitant Demands of Seamen, which enhances Freight, and which by Communication ſpreads and diffuſes it ſelf like a general Tax upon the whole Kingdom, by the Riſe of all Naval Commodities. I ſhall only give the Reader one particular In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance, that is in our <hi>Newcaſtle</hi>-Trade: According to the Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtom-Houſe Books, there is yearly imported into this City about <hi>320000</hi> Chaldron of Coals one Tear with another, and there is required for the bringing home of theſe Coals after the rate of <hi>12</hi> Men for every <hi>200</hi> Chaldron, and to each of theſe Men is commonly given, in Times of Peace, about <hi>35 s. per</hi> Voyage, which is uſually made (Wind and Weather conſidered) in a Month or Six Weeks time; but now during the War, the Demands of Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men are ſo high, that they now give them <hi>4</hi> or <hi>5 l.</hi> and ſometimes they are obliged to give them <hi>6</hi> and <hi>7 l. per</hi> Voyage; but ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſing the Wages at no higher Rate than <hi>4 l. 10 s.</hi> it will amount by calculation to above <hi>3 s. 3 d. ½.</hi> upon every Chaldron; ſo that computing the increaſe of Seamens Wages upon every Chal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dron of Coals brought into this Port, there is paid by this ſin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gle City of <hi>London,</hi> and Places adjacent, by the Riſe of that one Commodity only, above <hi>52500 l. per ann.</hi> to ſatisfie the extravagant Demands of Seamen, and which incourages them to hide, and keep out of the King's Service. This is but the Tax of one Commodity, only paid by this ſingle City and Places adjacent; but if it were poſſible to compute the Charge of the whole Kingdom, not only in this but in all other Naval Commo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dities, it would ſwell the Acount to a Prodigy, and be motive ſufficient for every worthy and publick ſpirited Patriot, to take care of his Country, and to free them from the Burthen and Op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſion of ſuch a Tax, that, for want of a due Regulation, is
<pb facs="tcp:47803:6"/>paid to maintain the Idleneſs and Luxury of Seamen. And of how great moment ſuch a general Relief and Eaſe of the Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject would be, in a time when we are engaged for our common Safety, to contribute our utmoſt for carrying on the War, may eaſily be conſidered, and whether ſuch a general Relief for Merchants, would not be a ſufficient compenſation for the <hi>Duty lately laid upon Tonnage.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:47803:7"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:47803:7" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>A REGULATION FOR SEAMEN, WHEREIN A Method is humbly propos'd, whereby their Majeſties Fleet may at all times be effectually mann'd, the Merchants more readily and cheaper ſerv'd, without having their Men at any time preſs'd or taken away, and all the Grievances and extraordinary Charges now attending both King and Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chant removed.</head>
            <p>WHEREAS the Manning of their Majeſties Fleet with a ſufficient Number of Seamen in time of War, has been always, and is ſtill found very difficult, beſides the great Charge his Majeſty is at in Preſſing of Men; and not only ſo, but when the Fleet is ſo Mann'd, the greateſt part of preſt Men are always ſeeking opportunities to deſert the Service, their Affections being more enclin'd to ſerve in Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chant-men, chiefly by reaſon of the great Wages which Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chants do give them in time of War: So that Seamen matter
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:47803:8"/>not if they looſe 5 or 6, ſometimes 12 Months Pay, from thoſe Ships they deſert, together with the further loſs of their Time whilſt they are hid on ſhoar (which it's believed one third part of our Seamen commonly are) in expectation of getting into ſome protected Merchant-man: And notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding it has been lately publiſhed in the Fleet, that <hi>whoſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever deſerts ſhall ſuffer death,</hi> yet they ſtill deſert when they have an opportunity, for which ſeveral have ſuffered.</p>
            <p>Now what is humbly propoſed hereafter, is a Method whereby, in time of War, their Majeſties Fleet may, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out Confuſion or Grievance, and that with much leſs Charge than they are now at in preſſing of Men, be all ſufficiently mann'd, and never want Seamen, the Merchants much ea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſier, cheaper, and better ſerved, and the Seamen have no Temptation to deſert or hide, and by conſequence have no occaſion to ſuffer the loſs of their Pay or their Lives; neither need their Majeſties Ships that are laid up in Winter be kept in pay, but might diſcharge the greateſt part of their Men as ſoon as they are in Harbour, which would eaſe the King of another great Charge, with many other Conveniences.</p>
            <p>The propoſed METHOD.</p>
            <p>Propoſition 1. <hi>That there be a Regiſter Office erected in every conſiderable Port in</hi> England, <hi>for regiſtring all Seamen, their Names, Age, Place of abode, Quality, and Ships they laſt ſerved in; and that there be particular Books kept in each Office for the reſpective Qualities of Men, one for Officers in general, and another for able Seamen, another for ordinary,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>And it is humbly propos'd, that the general Regiſter-Office at</hi> London <hi>be allowed</hi> 500 l. per ann. <hi>one Clerk at</hi> 100 l. <hi>and two or three other Clerks at</hi> 50 l. per ann. <hi>and two Meſſengers at</hi> 30 l. per ann. <hi>and
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:47803:8"/>that at all other Ports where it ſhall be thought convenient to erect other Offices; the Regiſter-Officer may be allowed from</hi> 100 l. <hi>to</hi> 300 l. per ann, <hi>and the Clerks proportion<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ably, according to the Buſineſs of the Port, and accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to which the Number of Clerks muſt be more or leſs.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>And that there be a Proclamation publiſhed throughout the Kingdom, to require and cauſe all Seamen within one Months time after ſuch Publication made, to repair to the ſaid Offices they neareſt reſide unto, and enter them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves therein. And if any Seaman ſhall refuſe to obey the ſaid Orders, and ſhall not within one Month come and enter himſelf in the ſaid Regiſter, nor give in a true account of his non-ability by reaſon of Sickneſs, or the like, that then all ſuch offending Seamen ſhall be obliged to ſerve<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> the King Six Months on board ſome of his Ships without Pay, and his Wages to go to the Cheſt of</hi> Chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham. <hi>And for the Encouragement of all ſuch Seamen that are unimployed, and ſhall come in ſpeedily and obey the ſaid Proclamation, every ſuch Seaman may be allowed ſuch free Gift or Bounty-Money as is hereafter mentioned,</hi> (viz.) <hi>For every able Seaman that enters himſelf with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in one Week after Proclamation</hi> 20 s. <hi>within two Weeks</hi> 15 s. <hi>within three Weeks</hi> 10 s. <hi>within a Month</hi> 5 s. <hi>That ſuch Bounty-Money ſhall be paid to each Seaman or his Aſſigns within one Month after he is entered on board any Ship, either Kings or Merchants, as ſhall be appointed them; and if they are appointed for the King's Service, then ſuch Sums to be paid by the Treaſurer of their Majeſties Navy; and if appointed for Merchant men, ſuch Sums to be allowed and paid them by the Comman<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders or Owners of ſuch Merchants Ship.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:47803:9"/>
               <hi>Argument</hi> 1. <hi>London</hi> being the Metropolis and chief place for Seamen, the Regiſter Officer will not only have abundantly more Buſineſs than the reſt, not only by rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon of the Scituation of the Place, but alſo by receiving the weekly Accompts of all the other Offices, therefore his Sallary is humbly propoſed at 500 <hi>l. per ann.</hi> And as to <hi>Briſtol</hi> and <hi>Newcaſtle,</hi> the Buſineſs will be very conſiderable there, which may be preſum'd to deſerve 300 <hi>l. per ann.</hi> And all others according to the Buſineſs of the Place, and the Clerks alſo accordingly 40 or 50 <hi>l. per ann.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>It would be very convenient and good that Seamen ſhould at firſt have ſome Encouragement for their ready Obe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dience to this Method, which would be of ſuch general Eaſe and Relief to all Perſons; and the Merchants cannot think much of giving (once) this Bounty-Money, when now they give a Sum far exceeding it.</p>
            <p>When once 'tis underſtood, as by Proclamation may be made mention, That no Seaman can have any Employment, except he regiſter himſelf in the Office, as hereafter appears; and what Encouragement there is to prompt their ſpeedy coming in, it may be preſumed that few or none at all will refuſe to enter themſelves, but that they will voluntarily and ſpeedily do it, by reaſon alſo of their Preference of Service, he being firſt to be employed that ſtands next on the Books; and when they find that there is no poſſibility for them to be employed otherwiſe, nor no place to turn themſelves in, but by coming to the Regiſter, they will ſoon think it bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter to come and enter themſelves, than to run the hazard of the Penalty, by being taken, or otherwiſe to ſtarve on ſhoar, eſpecially knowing, that by this Method they ſhall all have a fair and equal Chance, and the Advantages be the ſame into whatſoever Service they go; neither can a
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:47803:9"/>Seaman think of employing himſelf out of his Element; for there is no Service eaſily to be found, wherein he can have 15 or 18 <hi>l. per ann.</hi> Sallary, and his Victualing, like as in the Sea-ſervice.</p>
            <p>Prop. 2. <hi>That all the Commanders of the Kings and Merchants Ships and Veſſels, do within ten Days after the erection of the ſaid Offices, give in a true Liſt to each reſpective Office they are neareſt unto, of all the Men that particularly belong to each of their Ships, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>noting their Ages and Quality, that they may be regi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtred in the ſaid Offices, and thereupon receive Regiſter-Tickets, to be ſign'd and ſeal'd by the ſaid Regiſter-Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficer, that ſhall denote the Age and Quality of each Man, the Ship and Place, if Merchant-man, they are bound to; and that without ſuch Ticket, no Seaman do preſume to enter, ſerve, or continue himſelf on board of any Ship or Veſſel, either King's or Merchant-men, without the Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalty of ſerving the King Six Months on board ſome of his Ships, with Forfeiture of his Wages for that time to the Cheſt at</hi> Chatham.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Arg.</hi> 2. By giving Tickets to Seamen, it not only ſtrengthens the Power and Security of the Regiſter, with a great deal of eaſe, but it is a Convenience to the Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, and a great Security to Maſters of Ships, Houſhol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders or Inmates, who might otherwiſe, notwithſtanding all their Advertencies, fall under Penalties.</p>
            <p>The Penalty is propoſed at the forfeiture of 6 Months Wages, ſuppoſing nothing leſs would keep them to a ſenſe of their Duty, and that if they had any part of their Wages allowed them, they would ſcarcely find any Severity in their Puniſhment.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:47803:10"/>It is highly neceſſary that Penalties ſhould at firſt be in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>flicted to awe the Seamen, and to bring the Regulation in practice; but it's ſuppoſed that after a little time the Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thod will be ſo agreeable, that there will be few or none found guilty of any breach of the ſame.</p>
            <p>The Penalties are propoſed to go to the Cheſt at <hi>Chatham,</hi> that their Forfeitures may not fall to the Benefit of any others, but to the Uſe of themſelves in general, which is preſumed will prove to their better Content and Satisfaction.</p>
            <p>Prop. 3. <hi>That no Commander of any Merchant's Ship or Veſſel do give to, or agree with any able or ordinary Seamen,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>for any other Wages than as hereafter followeth,</hi> viz.</p>
            <list>
               <item>S. S.</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>An</hi> Able Seaman <hi>not above</hi> 30 <hi>nor leſs than</hi> 28 per <hi>Month.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>An</hi> Ordinary Seaman <hi>not above</hi> 26 <hi>nor leſs than</hi> 24 per <hi>Month.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>A</hi> Groomett <hi>not above</hi> 22 <hi>nor leſs than</hi> 20 per <hi>Month.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>A</hi> Landman <hi>not above</hi> 22 <hi>nor leſs than</hi> 18 per <hi>Month.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>A</hi> Boy <hi>not above</hi> 18 <hi>nor leſs than</hi> 15 per <hi>Month.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <p>
               <hi>and proportionable to his other Officers, according to the Burthen of the Ship, and number of Men ſhe carries.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Arg.</hi> 3: It's conceived that about 30 <hi>s. per</hi> Month for an able Seaman, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in Merchants pay may be equivalent to the King's, conſidering the Diſadvantages in Merchant-men, as 12 Months to the Year, no proviſion for Accidents if maimed, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> no ſhort Allowance upon victualling, nor Allowance for Cloaths if taken by the Enemy, Diſcount upon Damages, harder Labour, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And the reaſon why Merchants wages is propoſed to be fix'd and brought lower, is, becauſe it will be impoſſible for any true Regulation to be made without it.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:47803:10"/>For the exorbitant Wages that have been, all this War, given by Merchant-men, may truly be ſaid to have been the great cauſe of all the Grievances that King, Merchant and Subject in general, have long lain under, always complain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing but cannot help themſelves: for whilſt there is double or near treble the Pay in a Merchant-man, how can a Seaman be eaſie or contented to ſerve the King? will he not ſtudy and ſeek all ways and means to hide from and evade the Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice? or if taken and forced to ſerve the King, will he not ſtudy and take all opportunities to deſert? tho the Ruine of his Family, his Wages and his Life lie at ſtake for it. And though the Merchants do pay and continue their high Wages, yet they cannot be ſaid to be in the fault neither, having no power to help themſelves; for whilſt the King muſt make uſe of the Power of Preſſing, for the getting his Ships man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned, (as it is requiſite, for the Safety of the Nation, he ſhould;) ſo on the other ſide, a Merchant would never be mann'd, could he not find out a way that would ballance the King's Power: the force of which, for want of other, he places in his Money, thus through the oppoſition of each other, the publick Calamity, and a long Train of Grievan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces follow.</p>
            <p>To remedy which, no expedient can be found, until the Merchants can be ſupply'd as effectually as the King, and the Wages of both be brought and kept to an intrinſick Ballance. The firſt of which (as is preſumed) cannot be done without a <hi>Regiſter;</hi> and the laſt cannot be fix'd or kept except the Seamen be obliged to paſs through, and the Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chants be obliged to take them at the <hi>Regiſter,</hi> or the like. And why there ſhould not be ſuch a Regulation made, as is propoſed, to prevent it, may be enquired into.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Firſt,</hi> The King and Subject, in general, will have no reaſon but to like it; for the King would not only be well manned at all times, but be conſiderably eaſed in his Revenue, by ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:47803:11"/>away the great Charge of Impreſſing. And as to the Subject in general, they would greatly be eaſed in the price of all Naval Comodities, which by the exorbitant Wages of Seamen, have been raiſed, and which, by conſequence, upon this Regulation would fall lower.</p>
            <p>Then for the Merchant in particular, he has no reaſon to be diſcontented at it, becauſe he will have as good Men as the King, ready found for him, free from being preſt, and eaſed in his extravagant Wages, now given.</p>
            <p>And as for the Seamen, the Generality of them will have no occaſion to complain, for they will all have an equal Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vantage, without murmuring or repining, in the Kings Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice; and as to thoſe that skulk and hide to avoid the King's Service, conſidering their Loſs of Pay, Expences in Victuals <hi>&amp;c.</hi> whilſt they are hid on Shoar, and their being preſt into the King's Service upon their return home, after which they are kept like Priſoners on board, without being permitted to go home to their Wifes or Families, nor receive any com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fort of their Voyages, all theſe Hardſhips that the Seamen now run through, beſides their great Loſs many times of their Wages, and ſometimes of their Lives, occaſioned by their deſerting the King's Service; all theſe things conſidered, it would be really better, and perhaps more advantagious for them, that no ſuch Temptation of high Wages were: and tho this Regulation propoſed, may ſeem a little harſh to them upon firſt hearing, yet a very little Conſideration will make them like it.</p>
            <p>And to prove that Merchants Wages can never be fix'd lower, nor kept to a ballance, and that no true Regulation can be made, but by ſuch like Method as is propoſed in theſe Papers, may thus be demonſtrated,</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Firſt,</hi> Except the Seamen be obliged to paſs through ſome Regiſter, or the like, and the Merchant alſo be obliged to take them there, no Reſtriction, nor Penalty can ſecure or
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:47803:11"/>hinder the riſe of Merchants Wages; and if there was an Order made ever ſo ſtrict to bind the Merchants from giving, and the Seamen from demanding higher Wages, without be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing obliged at the <hi>Regiſter,</hi> it would be ineffectual.</p>
            <p>For if Merchants and Seamen were at their liberty to chuſe one another, without being thus obliged, the Seamen (having their high Wages freſh in their memories) would be unwilling to go into the Merchants ſervice for ſuch ſmall Wages, and lie longer idling on ſhore; and the Merchants, to have their Ships mann'd, would, either for the advantage of better Seamen, or for being earlier fitted to Sea, be prom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pted ſtill to raiſe their Wages (by Connivance.) And the ſame reaſons for the Seamens exorbitant Demands, would be then, as now; and, by conſequence, the Prejudice and Grievance to their Majeſties and the Subject in general would follow. The Allurements and Temptations of deſerting their Majeſties Service being ſtill the ſame.</p>
            <p>And to think upon a Penalty upon the Merchants or Seamen to prevent it; it would be altogether impracticable, for there can be no Diſcoverers of ſuch Connivance but them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, and they being both agreed will never do it; neither would it be reaſonable that a Merchant ſhould lie at the mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cy of any Seaman, that may falſly ſwear, for the ſake of a Reward, that ſuch Merchant did connive with him.</p>
            <p>Prop. 4, <hi>That no Commander of any Merchant ſhip or Veſſel do preſume to entertain any one Seaman otherwiſe than ſhall be ordered him, and tickeited for him from ſome</hi> Regiſter-Office, <hi>and that all Merchant-men be obliged to take in one 5th or 6th part Land-men, or ſuch a Number as ſhall from time to time be thought meet, and that if any Commander of any Merchant-ſhip or Veſſel, ſhall preſume to take in, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceal or entertain any one Seaman, that is unticketed or not appointed for him by the ſaid</hi> Office, <hi>that then the ſaid
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:47803:12"/>Commander ſhall forfeit and be obliged to pay after the rate of</hi> 6 l. per month, <hi>for every ſuch Seaman during the time he was on board him: one Moiety of the ſaid For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feiture to be paid to the Diſcoverer, and the other to the Cheſt of</hi> Chatham.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And that if any Seaman ſhall preſume to enter himſelf on board any Ship or Veſſel whatſoever, for the ſpace of ſix days, without being ticketted for it by the ſaid Office, that then every ſuch Seaman ſhall forfeit and be obliged to pay to the Diſcoverer, after the rate of</hi> 20 s. per <hi>Month, for all the time of his unticketed Service; and moreover be obliged to ſerve the King ſix months without Pay, and his Wages to go to the Cheſt.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Arg.</hi> 4. The Lords of the Admiralty, who are plac'd on an Eminence, from whence they deſcry all the Neceſſities of of the State, in reſpect to Naval Affairs, may, by this Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gulation, eaſily foreſee and prevent all the Confuſion and Dangers, which, for want of a due and regular Diviſion of Seamen, might otherwiſe accrue; and from time to time be able to proportion ſuch numbers of Land-men to them as ſhall beſt conſiſt with the ſafety of the Kingdom, Benefit of Commerce, and Nurſery of Seamen.</p>
            <p>By impoſing a Penalty both upon Merchants and Seamen too, all thought and probability of asking by the one, and conſenting by the other is taken away.</p>
            <p>Prop. 5th. <hi>That all the King's Ships when they diſcharge any Men, do give into the Office that is neareſt unto them, a qualified Liſt of ſuch Men they diſcharge, mentioning their Names, Ages, Quality, when and where they laſt ſerved, and places of abode, and that the Lieutenant of the ſaid Man of War, do go with them when diſcharged, and ſee them anſwer to their Names, and that then ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:47803:12"/>Tickets ſhall be delivered to the Men, limiting a certain time for them to go about their own Occaſions, at the expiration of which time, if not call'd ſooner, they are to attend again for new Tickets, and if Occa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion requires their Attendance ſooner than their time limited, they ſhall have Summons ſent and left for them at their places of aboad; beſides which Summons, a pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Liſt ſhall be hung up at the Office of all thoſe Seamen whoſe turn it is next to be employed, mentioning their Names, Ages, Qualities, and from whence, and when they were laſt diſcharged, and ſuch a competent number of Men ſhall be put therein from time to time as ſhall be thought fit, and the Occaſion of the Service require.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That ſix Months after the erection of the ſaid Offices, Orders, may be iſſued out from the Lords of the Admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ralty, directed to all ſuch Commanders of any of Their Majeſties Ships who ſhall come into any Port to re-fit or clean, (excepting thoſe Ships that are to be diſchargedin the Winter) that the one half of all ſuch Seamen, belonging to them, beginning with thoſe that ſtand</hi> firſt on the Books, <hi>and which have ſerved above a Twelve Month on Board ſuch Ships, may have their Liberty to be diſcharged, if they deſire it, provided that they immediately enter themſelves into the next Regiſter Office, and that theſe Orders be continued alternatively every ſix Months, or as near it as poſſible.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Arg.</hi> 5. By this means the great Plague of being turn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed over from Ship to Ship ceaſes, and by having their whole Ship's Crew enter'd together at the Office when it falls to their Turns again, to be employ'd either in the King's or Merchants Service, for which they will have a fair and equal Chance, their old Ship Mates will come together again, which will not be a little Pleaſure and Satisfaction to Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men,
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:47803:13"/>and if any one of them is Tardy and Runs into a Penalty, they generally knowing one another's Haunts, they are the moſt likely to find out the Offender, and get the Reward; beſides, if any Perſon's Summons for Service ſhould by any Accident miſcarry, he will ſoon have notice of it by the others.</p>
            <p>Seamen by being thus reliev'd, will not be always con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fin'd to one particular Ship, wherein for ſome Reaſons they may be uneaſy, but will have their Liberty of going into any other of the King's Ships that can entertain them, or take their Chance at the Office, and by giving Liberty to one half only to be diſcharg'd at a time, it will be to the greater Eaſe and Satisfaction of the Commanders. <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But the high Wages of Merchants being fix'd and brought lower, the old Allurements and Temptations will be taken away, and by conſequence but very few will deſire to leave the King's Service, and thereby be the leſs trouble to the Regiſter.</p>
            <p>Prop. 6. <hi>That all the Commanders of Merchant-men, upon their return from their reſpective Voyages, and upon the diſcharge of their men, do go with them, to the next</hi> Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice, <hi>and give in a true Liſt of them; rating all ſuch as were not Officers according as he ſhall think they deſerve, either Able, Ordinary, or otherwiſe; and ſee them anſwer to their Names: upon which they are to receive Abſent Tickets, as above; thoſe that have been Officers, to have Certificates of their good Behaviour from their Comman<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders, if not, to be entred as Able Seamen only.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That if any Seam an be diſcharged into any</hi> Regiſter-Office, <hi>and ſhall deſire to be removed into any other</hi> Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſter-Office <hi>(to attend for Service) that is nearer to his uſual place of abode, that then ſuch Seamen ſhall have a</hi> Transfer Ticket <hi>given him for that purpoſe to be made, limiting a time for his Paſſage.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="13" facs="tcp:47803:13"/>
               <hi>That all the Commanders of Merchant-men, before the Diſcharge of their Men, do give into the next</hi> Office, <hi>a true Account, upon the Oath of himſelf and Mate, of all the Men he at any time hath had in his ſervice, from his firſt going out to his return home, and of what Wages is particularly due to each of them, and that he be obliged not to pay any of them, until they have entred themſelves in the</hi> Regiſter, <hi>and can produce</hi> Entry-Tickets <hi>of it, and that then he reſerve one Tenth part of ſuch Seamens Wages, to be paid into the</hi> Regiſter-Office, <hi>there to be kept for them until ſuch time as they are again ordered for Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice by the</hi> Regiſter. <hi>And if it appears, upon the Master's account given, that any of his men are abſent that have at any time run away from him, that then the</hi> full <hi>of ſuch abſent Seamens Wages be paid into the</hi> Office, <hi>for the uſe of the Cheſt of</hi> Chatham, <hi>his Wages to be computed not as the Maſter pleaſes, but according to the rate of his other like Seament wages, and to be reckoned from the time of his Entry to his abſenting himſelf. And that the Tenth part likewiſe of all ſuch Seamens Wages that are paid and diſcharg'd out of the King's Service, be paid by the Treaſurer of their Majeſties Navy into the</hi> Regiſter-Office, <hi>for the purpoſes aforeſaid.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>And that if it ſo happen that any of the ſaid Seamen ſhall not fall to be employed in three months, or ſhall have leave to quit the Service, that then ſuch Money ſhall be paid them upon demand.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That the Tenth part of ſuch Wages, ſhall continue to be paid into the</hi> Regiſter, <hi>only during time of War.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>It is alſo humbly propoſed, for the Encouragement of all Seamen in the Merchants Service, that</hi> 2 d. per month <hi>upon all Seamens Wages, as well in Peace as War may be deducted to go to the Cheſt at</hi> Chatham; <hi>and all Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men to have the ſame Benefit as thoſe in the King's Service upon the account of Wounds, Bruiſes, or any other accidents.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="14" facs="tcp:47803:14"/>
               <hi>Arg.</hi> 6. It is neceſſary that the Commanders of Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chant-men ſhould give all the Officers Certificates of their good behaviour, for the Satisfaction of ſuch Merchant-men, whoſe turn afterwards may be to take them, and it may be preſum'd, that there will be no Commander but what will be careful in giving their Certificates without Favour or Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fection, becauſe he knows not, but he may ſuffer himſelf by the ſame breach of publick Faith, beſides his being obnoxi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous to the reproaches of all ſuch of his Fraternity, that may hear of it. Seamen being often taken in at one Port, and diſcharged at another, may thus be ſet on ſhoar ſome di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance from their uſual places of aboad, and 'tis but reaſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able they ſhould have the Comforts of their Friends and Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>milies whilſt aſhoar.</p>
            <p>The reſerving ſome part of the Seamens Wages will be a check upon them, and draw them to a Love of the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſter, as uſually they do all thoſe places from whence their Money comes, eſpecially if they want it; and beſides, it will do them a greater Kindneſs than perhaps they would do themſelves, by ſaving ſome part of their Money towards their fitting out again, if they ſhould want it, and the Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men cannot complain for want of its preſent Payment, ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving all the reſt of their Money in their Pockets.</p>
            <p>It may be ſuppoſed, that the loſs of a Seaman, with pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing notwithſtanding all his Wages that is due to him, will be Cauſe ſufficient to oblige a Commander to look after his Men, who may run away from him, and not be in his Power to prevent it; but 'its preſumed, that the loſs of their Wages, and the love of their Native Country, will keep them from ſuch thoughts.</p>
            <p>The Chief thing that hath hitherto diſcouraged Seamen from Fighting in Merchant-men is, that they know if they do Fight, and are wounded or utterly diſabled, no Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſideration
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:47803:14"/>will be given, nor Allowance made to ſupport them, which if ſuch Deductions for that purpoſe were made, it may be hoped that the Merchants Ships would be better Defended.</p>
            <p>There may perhaps be ſome Objection againſt the fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>going Propoſal, that by paying the tenth part of Seamens Wages into the Regiſter Office, it would create another great Charge of a Treaſurer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> To which I anſwer, That it will need no additional Charge, nor no Treaſurer but the Regiſter, and were the Sums much larger, ſecure and conve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venient Methods may be taken for it with little or no Charge to the Office.</p>
            <p>Prop. 7. <hi>That always the Men that are diſcharged from any Office, be from time to time, thoſe that ſtand firſt upon the Regiſter. And to the end that all Seamen may have e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>qual Fortune and Advantage, they are to take their courſe for Employment according as it falls out, either into their Majeſties or Merchants Service, as they are entred into the</hi> Regiſter-Book, <hi>except ſuch as ſhall voluntarily paſs through any</hi> Regiſter-Office <hi>into their Majeſties Service, which all Seamen out of Employ, and not appointed for Service, ſhall at all times, tho it be not their Turn to be employed, have liberty ſo to go on board which of their Majeſties Ships that can entertain them, or they have a deſire to ſerve in. And if any Seaman ſhall be unwilling to go any foreign Voyage that ſhall be appointed him, he may change with any other Seaman that is willing, that ſtands after him, ſetting him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf in the ſaid willing Seamans Place.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That all ſuch Seamen, who are outward bound in the King's Service, upon any foreign Voyages, and ſhall ſtay out longer than one Year; that all ſuch Seamen, during the time that they are out, may be allowed</hi> 12 d. per mon. <hi>more, as an Addition to their uſual Wages; and that
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:47803:15"/>one Moiety of ſuch Seamens Wages accruing due upon their foreign Voyages, may be paid every</hi> 6 <hi>months, to ſuch Seamens Wives, or ſuch other Perſons, as they ſhall, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore their departure, nominate and aſſign to the Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners of their Majeſties Navy, or ſome Regiſter-Officer, And that the firſt</hi> 6 <hi>months Payment may begin at the Expiration of</hi> 12 <hi>months from their departure.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Arg.</hi> 7. By giving Liberty for Seamen to go into the King's Service at any time, it may in a little time whol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly man the Fleet with Volunteers, which undoubtedly would prove to the better Safety and Honour of our Nation; for ſuch willing Men will heartily and chearfully look their Enemies in the Face, whereas Preſs'd Men having no mind to Fight, are rather for running down into the Hold; and when Seamen once flinch or run from their Poſts, it is a dangerous Preſident, and the many late evil effects of this kind may ſufficiently convince us of the Truth and ill Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſequences of it.</p>
            <p>The uncertainties of Seamens healths, and the hardſhip they may endure in foreign Voyages, together with the long abſence from their Familes or Friends, may well deſerve an Addition to their Wages, and if their Wives and Families had but the benefit of their half pay, to preſerve them from the want and Neceſſities, that they might otherwiſe be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duced to, 'twould make them go with the greater Ala<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crity.</p>
            <p>Prop. 8. <hi>That as often as there ſhall be ocaſion for Seamen, either for their Majeſties or Merchant Ships, beſides the Publick Liſt aforementioned, Summons ſhall be ſent to the reſpective places of the ſaid Seamens abode, mentioning their day and time for attendance to be appointed for Service; and that if any Seaman do not obſerve the ſaid
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:47803:15"/>Summons except due proof made of Nonability upon ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count of Sickneſs or the like (and then they are to give no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice of it to the next Regiſter) that then the ſaid Perſons not appearing, Warrants may be iſſued out to apprehend and take them, and the ſaid Offender be obliged to ſerve the King</hi> 6 <hi>months without Wages, and his Pay to go to the Cheſt; but if any Seaman ſhall incur the Penalty, either by diſobeying the ſaid Summons, or for not entring him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf according to Proclamation, and ſhall, within</hi> 20 <hi>days after his forfeiture, ſurrender himſelf voluntarily to the next</hi> Regiſter-Office, <hi>it may be left to the Power of the</hi> Regiſter <hi>to mitigate his Penalty, but not to ſet it lower than one month's Service. And if any Houſholder or Inmate ſhall preſume to conceal or entertain any Seaman, that is not ticketted by the</hi> Regiſter-Office <hi>for ſerving in ſome Ship, or ticketted for his Attendance on ſhore till his turn comes to be employed, or he whoſe time in the ſaid Ticket for Attendance is expired; and does not immediately give notice of it to the next</hi> Regiſter, <hi>that then the ſaid Houſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holder or Inmate, in whoſe Houſe or Lodgings, the ſaid Seaman is found to have been entertain'd, ſhall be obli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged to pay the ſum of</hi> 5 l. <hi>or to ſuffer three months Impri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonment without Bail or Main-priſe, provided the ſaid Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man has been there for the ſpace of three days and proof can be made that he was known to the ſaid Houſholder or In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mate to be a Seaman, and after ſuch Proof made, if the ſaid Houſholder or Inmate ſhall refuſe to pay the ſaid Penal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, or ſhall refuſe to ſurrender himſelf, that then a Warrant may be iſſued out, to make Diſtreſs and Sale of the ſaid Offenders Goods, for the ſaid Penalty, the Overplus, if any, to be returned: one Moiety whereof ſhall be paid to the Diſcoverer of ſuch concealed Seaman, and the other to the Cheſt; but if no Diſtreſs can be made, the Diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verer ſhall then receive the ſum of</hi> 50 s. <hi>out of the ſaid
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:47803:16"/>Seaman's Six Months Wages, which ſhall immediately be aſſign'd to the Diſcoverer by Ticket by the next Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſter Office, and ſhall be allowed to the ſaid Diſcoverer or his Aſſigns, when the ſaid Wages ſhall become payable.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Arg.</hi> 8. By impoſing a Penalty upon the Entertainers of Seamen, a Seaman will have no Harbour, for his Friends will not harbour him for their own ſakes; and to conceal himſelf and quality amongſt Strangers, will be uncomfort<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able, and to think of any other Employment out of his own Element will be difficult and diſcouraging.</p>
            <p>A Seaman may be concealed in the Lodging of an In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mate, where all the Goods may not be worth five Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, and therefore unable to pay five Pounds, but there is no reaſon that ſuch an Offender ſhould paſs unpuniſhed, or the Diſcoverer go without his Reward.</p>
            <p>Prop. 8. <hi>That the Commanders of all Their Majeſties Ships do give the Men they give leave to be abſent from their Ships, Regiſter Tickets for that purpoſe to be made, and without they have ſuch Tickets, no Houſholder or Inmate is to entertain any Seaman for the ſpace of two days, Sickneſs to be excepted, and then to give notice of it to the next Regiſter, under the Penalty as in the Caſe of a conceal'd Seamen, that if any Seaman ſhall preſume to abſent himſelf without ſuch Ticket of Leave from his Commander, or ſhall ſtay longer than the ſaid Regiſter Ticket of Leave ſhall mention, that ſuch Seamen ſhall be obliged to ſerve the King for a certain time, during which, his Pay ſhall be forfeited to the Cheſt, not ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding Six Months, according to the nature and degree of his Offence, and at the Deſcretion of his Captain, to whom he belongs.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="19" facs="tcp:47803:16"/>
               <hi>Arg.</hi> 9. It is fit that Seamen ſhould be Ticketted, not only to prevent the Seamen being abſent from their Duty longer than their Leave given them, but alſo to prevent any ſhiſting Seaman from paſſing under a pretence that he belongs to a Man of War, and therefore not Ticketted, by which means ſome Men will evade coming to the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſter Office, if Men of Wars Men were not alſo Ticket<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, that have leave to go on ſhoar.</p>
            <p>Prop. 10. <hi>That the Commander of all Merchant men ſhall have an Order from the Admiralty of what num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers of Seamen, and what Landmen, &amp;c. they ſhall take in. That the Commanders of all Merchant-men may have the Liberty to chooſe their Mate where they pleaſe, and if the ſaid Mate be entered into any Office, he ſhall be diſcharged though it be not his turn to be employed, or out of any of the King's Ships, if he deſires his Mate from thence, but as to all his other Officers, he ſhall chooſe them only as the Order to the Regiſter for his Men ſhall ſignify, out of double the number of the Complement as ſhall be ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed for him, out of thoſe which ſtand next in courſe upon the Regiſter, unleſs ſuch as he can by Applica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion made, get out of Men of War, to be diſcharged to him for their Preferment, and if ſo, ſuch to paſs to him through the Office where he has the reſt of his Men.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That for the Encouragement of ſuch Seamen as have been Officers in Merchant-man, and would voluntarily ſerve their Majeſties, but that they are unwilling to be at all Calls under the commands of a Boatſwain, and for the encouragement of thoſe who ſhall improve them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, and are capable of ſubaltern Offices. And
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:47803:17"/>that the Commanders of their Majeſties Ships do take notice of ſuch Men that doth accordingly behave themſelves, and rate them extraordinary to be paid ſomething</hi> per <hi>Month more, than is now paid able Seamen, and ſuch to be quartered in ſome little Poſt in time of Fight, as Chief at a great Gun, and that the Complement of ſuch Men do never exceed the third part of the number of the Guns that each Ship car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries, and that thoſe Men upon application made by Merchant men, may be diſcharged to them for Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers, if they like not thoſe that ſtand next on courſe at the Office as aforeſaid.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Arg.</hi> 10. It is reaſonable that a Maſter ſhould not be confin'd to his Mate, by reaſon of the great Truſt that is repos'd in the Maſter, and which in caſe of Mortality, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcends to his Mate. As to his other Officers, he has a dou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Choice, beſides a Liberty by application made, and leave granted to have them out of a Man of War, or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe, if he ſhall find any of his Men deſerving or capa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, he may preſer them.</p>
            <p>It is neceſſary that ſome further encouragement ſnould be given to ſuch good and able Seamen, as have been Officers in Merchant-men, and are willing to ſerve the King; for thoſe Seamen who for their Deſerts have had a diſtinction and been preferred in a Merchant man, will think it hard to be put back before the Maſt upon the ſame level with others in a Man of War, for this reaſon a diſtinction is propoſed both in Pay and Poſt, and ſuch would be very uſeful in ſuch Poſts in time of Fight, which together with the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Officers as is uſually quartered at the Guns, might make one to the Command of each Gun.</p>
            <p>Prop. 11. <hi>That all Merchant-men may have their liberty
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:47803:17"/>to take their Land men where they pleaſe, but if they cannot find any themſelves, they are to be ſupply'd at the Office, to which end there may be certain Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panies always kept, maintained, and recruited by the King for the breeding of Seamen to ſupply ſuch Occaſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, and that ſuch Companies may be raiſed by beat of Drum, as the Marines, to be bred up and inſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted at the King's Tards, and to be commanded by ſome ſuperannuated Boatſwain and an Aſſiſtant; who ſhall daily receive Orders for their Employment from the Maſter of Attendance, as he ſhall ſee occaſion, and be ordered by the Commiſſioners of the Tard (if any) and ſuch men to be employed</hi> 6 <hi>or</hi> 7 <hi>hours in the day, and to receive</hi> 18 d. per day.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>That beſides thoſe Land men kept at the King's yards, there be alſo certain Numbers kept at every other Port where there is a</hi> Regiſter Office, <hi>and to be paid and quartered, according to the ſame rate as the King's Foot-Soldiers are; and to be permitted by leave of the</hi> Regiſter, <hi>to work on board any Ships or Veſſels that may have occaſion for their Help, and what they ſo earn to be moreover to their own Advantage.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>That for the Encouragement of Marines, as well as Land men, on board the King's Ships, and for the breed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of Seamen, it may be ſo ordered, that all the Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tains of Men of War do conſlitute and appoint two Maſters each Watch, one skill'd in the Theorick and the other in the Practick part of Sailing, to take upon them the Command of, and to teach and inſtruct the Marines, as well as the other Land-men; and that the Marines be discharged from their Companies, and en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tred as Seamen on the Ships Books, as ſoon as they ſhall be recommended by the ſubaltern Officers, to the Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain, as deſerving it.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="22" facs="tcp:47803:18"/>
               <hi>Arg.</hi> 11. Of how great uſe and abſolute neceſſity ſuch a Proviſion and Nurſery of Seamen would be, is obvious to every Man; and that they might be eaſily raiſed is no que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtion; for by liſting themſelves here, they are ſure to be put into the way of a good Livelyhood, and, if induſtrious, of good Preſerment, and are as free from any further Obligation, after they are entred on Ship-board, as any Seaman in <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land;</hi> for the ſake of which great numbers would come in, and in a little time choice and exception might be made of liking them; that by their employ at the King's yards and their Duty on ſhip-board, they would, in a little time, be made fit for ſervice; and diſcharging always thoſe that have been longeſt upon the Books, the King's Fleet and Merchants would always be mann'd by willing and ready Men; 'tis humbly propoſed that there may be maintained at the King's yards and other places at leaſt 1000 men in pay, out of which there may be drawn 100 every Week, more or leſs, as the Service re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quires, ſo that there may be drawn 5000 men <hi>per Annum,</hi> if required, and theſe men being generally employed in Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mens buſineſs, will make them ready and fit for Service, a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt they are drawn on board.</p>
            <p>By this means the King may have 5000 men every year raiſed as a Recruit for Seamen, which will be maintained and ready upon all occaſions, with no great charge to the King, thoſe in the King's yards earning good part of their Pay.</p>
            <p>That the Marines, as well as Land-men, on board the King's Ships, be carefully inſtructed in all parts of Sailing, is undoubtedly neceſſary; but the diſcharging the Marines may be left diſcretionally.</p>
            <p>Prop. 12. <hi>That no Merchant-man preſume to take in any Land-men, except they be firſt entered in the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſter-Office, where a Book for Landmen may be kept
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:47803:18"/>on purpoſe, under the ſame Penalty as for an unticketed Seaman; that if any able Seaman ſhall, under pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence of being a Landman, enter himſelf as ſuch in the Regiſter, and by Connivance receive larger Wages from the Commander, that then, upon due proof made of his being ſuch an able Seaman, he ſhall up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the return of his Voyage forfeit two third parts of his Pay due to him, one part to the Diſcoverer or Diſcoverers of ſuch able Seaman, and the other part to the Cheſt, and farther be obliged to ſerve the King</hi> 6 <hi>Months for half Pay, and the other half to go to the Cheſt.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>And to the end that ſuch Offenders may be diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered, a Liſt of all the Ships Company, as qualified, may be ſigned and ſealed by the Regiſter, and publick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly be affixed to ſome part of the ſaid Merchant-ſhip, which if blotted, torn, or otherwiſe made illegible, the Maſter ſhall be obliged, under the Penalty of</hi> 20l. <hi>to ſet up another Copy within four Days after No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice given.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Arg.</hi> 12. This Liſt will be a ſufficient Check both up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the Maſter and the Seaman; that no Fraud can be, but may eaſily be diſcovered.</p>
            <p>Prop. 13. <hi>That all the Regiſter-Offices do every Week or as often as it ſhall be thought meet, give into the general Regiſter Office at</hi> London, <hi>a Liſt of what Numbers of Men, and what Quality they are of, that are weekly employed by them; and alſo what Num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers and Quality they are of that ſtand unemployed on their Books.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="24" facs="tcp:47803:19"/>
               <hi>Arg.</hi> 13. Of how great uſe this will be to anſwer all Emergeneies, and to regulate all Naval Affairs, need not here be mentioned, it being very obvious to all judicious Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons.</p>
            <p>Prop. 14. <hi>That the Entry, Abſent, and Transfer-Tic<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kets for the ſaid Regiſter Office, and Abſent-Tickets for the Fleet be printed by a Printer appointed on purpoſe, that the General Regiſter under his Hand do appoint what Numbers at any time ſhall be printed, and no more.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Arg.</hi> 14. Theſe Tickers will, in a little time, be uni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſally known, to the great Eaſe and Security of Seamen and Subject in general; and that they may be the better kept from counterſeiting, they may be printed by Copper-Plates, to be kept at the Office.</p>
            <p>Prop. 15. <hi>That no Seaman be obliged to enter him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf in the ſaid Regiſter, and be forced to go to Sea, or ſuffer any Penalty for not doing ſo; but ſuch as have ſerved as Seaman within a Year laſt paſt; that no Seaman quit the ſaid Service, but ſuch as can ſhew good reaſon, and have leave ſo to do from the Lords of the Admiralty, or from ſome other Perſons appoin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted by them.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Arg.</hi> 15. It would be unreaſonable for one that was a Seaman three or four Years ago, more or leſs, and is now fall'n into ſome other Employ on Land, for him to be ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liged to go to Sea; and it would be needleſs to give him and the Office an unneceſſary trouble to be diſcharged; neither is it reaſonable that any Seaman ſhould quit the Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice without leave from the Lords of the Admiralty, or
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:47803:19"/>ſome others appointed by them, which may be a Regi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter-Officer, the next Juſtice of Peace, and a Captain of a Man or War, which being joyned together, may determine ſuch Matters, and for that purpoſe may be conven'd as often as there ſhall be an occaſion.</p>
            <p>☞ <hi>That the ſame Method as is uſed for Seamen, may be for</hi> Shipwrights, Caulkers, Rope makers, Sayl-makers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>I Shall not enumerate the many Advantages that might accrue by ſuch a Regulation, but only anſwer theſe three following <hi>Objections,</hi> viz.</p>
            <list>
               <item>Firſt, <hi>That by thus obliging Seamen, it looks like an In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fringement upon the Liberty of the Subject.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Secondly, <hi>That by lowering of Seamens Wages, we ſhall drive them all into foreign Services.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Thirdly, <hi>That the War is now almoſt at an end, and we had better bear the Grievance a little longer, rather than charge our ſelves with any new Project now, that can be of little or no uſe to us in times of Peace.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <p>
               <hi>Objection 1.</hi> That by thus obliging Seamen, it looks like an Infringement upon the Liberty of the Subject.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſwer.</hi> Liberty is a popular Argument indeed, and there ought to be a due Reſpect to it; but whether the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gulation propos'd doth not rather <hi>enlarge</hi> than <hi>entrench</hi> upon
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:47803:20"/>the Liberty of the Subject, is worth our preſent Enquiry.</p>
            <p>By the King's Royal Prerogative, and the Conſent of all Ages, a Power is inveſted in him to preſs Seamen upon all Emergencies, where the Safety of the Kingdom is con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern'd, and by this Power all Seamen are <hi>obliged</hi> to ſerve him, and the great Aſſembly of the Nation have thought fit to give it this additional Power to ſtrengthen it; <hi>That whatſoever Seaman deſerts their Majeſties Service, ſhall ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fer Death.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Thus every Seaman is now <hi>obliged</hi> to ſerve the King, and the Deſertion of ſuch Service is put under a more ſad and mournful Penalty than is here propos'd, which there ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver would be any more cauſe for, were the Method propos'd eſtabliſh'd: How far then ought the tragick and untimely End of ſuch Men to move us, eſpecially when Methods are found out for their Safety and Preſervation?</p>
            <p>Thus the Liberty of the Subject would be no more in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fringed than it is already, and a grievous Penalty would be removed.</p>
            <p>But there is further a real Argument for this Method pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſed, in reſpect to the Liberty of the Subject; for by the power of the Preſs, there is oft made no diſtinction, (for Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men cannot be known by their Faces) but Land men as well as Seamen are hurried away to the great detriment of ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny, and againſt the <hi>true Liberty</hi> of the Subject; and not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding ſtrict Orders are frequently iſſued out from the Lords of the Admiralty, that no ſuch violation ſhould be made, yet it is daily practiſed, and the Subject daily ſuffers.</p>
            <p>And indeed had there been no ſuch Violence us'd, a great part of our Fleet muſt have been unmann'd, and were it not ſtill continued, for want of a better method to breed Sailers, our Ships would ſoon feel the Want of Men; for the Boys, in the King's and the Merchants Ships, would
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:47803:20"/>never grow faſt enough to ſupply the yearly Decay and Loſs of them.</p>
            <p>Therefore it may eaſily appear how highly neceſſary it is that ſome Expedient ſhould be found out for manning the King's Fleet, without Preſſing, and that ſome other method ſhould be taken, for the more effectual breeding of Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, to ſecure both the Safety of the Kingdom, and Liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of the Subject.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Object. 2.</hi> We ſhould drive all our Seamen into Foreign Services, by reaſon of our low Wages.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſw.</hi> Firſt, They would be terrified from deſerting the ſervice, by the Act of Parliament, for that purpoſe made, and ſtill in force againſt them.</p>
            <p>For, if I am not miſtaken, there is an Act of Parliament that whatſoever Seaman abſents himſelf, without leave, from the ſervice of this Kingdom, in time of War, and ſhall en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gage himſelf, or take pay under any Foreign Prince or Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tentate whatſoever, that ſuch Seaman ſhall ſuffer Death. If there be ſuch a Law (as it is requiſite there ſhould) then ſuch Publication ought to be made of it, by ſetting it up in every Ship, or elſewhere, that no Seaman might be ig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>norant.</p>
            <p>But if there were no ſuch Act to over aw them, would not the natural Love that Seamen have for their Native Country reſtrain them from any ſuch thoughts? Would they be contented to loſe what pay is actually due to them, in hopes to get more by deſerting their ſhip, in a Foreign Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try, where they muſt not think to return to <hi>Old England</hi> any more, the place that they ſo affectionately talk of when they are abroad? Would they be contented not only to for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſake their own Country, but their Families, Friends and Acquaintance, to live amongſt Strangers, in an uncouth and
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:47803:21"/>untelligible Language, and all for the ſake of a little more Wages, which he knows not neither how long 'twill laſt? The experience of theſe things hath ſufficiently convinced us to the contrary, and that it muſt be great and inſufferable Hardſhips indeed, that will make a Seaman deſert his Native Country; for during all this War, of ſo many thouſand Seamen, that have been carried into <hi>St. Maloes,</hi> notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding they have endured very great Hardſhips there, and have been continually offered and tempted with 4 or 5 <hi>l. per month</hi> pay, yet none will engage in their ſervice, and many of them have afterwards, upon their return home, entred themſelves in the King's ſervice.</p>
            <p>But yet, after all, if there ſhould be ſome few, contrary to the common Inclination of Seamen, deſert, would it be of ſufficient force to continue the great Tax and Oppreſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, that they put upon Merchants, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> by their exorbitant Wages; and would there not be many more Seamen bred by this method, than would deſert by it? and ſhall it be ſaid that the Deſertion of a few men is reaſon ſufficient to ſtand in competition, and to keep the many Grievances on foot, that might otherwiſe be removed?</p>
            <p>And is it not now as reaſonable and neceſſary, that Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mens Wages, in reſpect to Merchants, ſhould be aſcertain'd and fix'd, as well as <hi>Carmens, Coachmens, Watermens,</hi> and the like, who at certain Rates are obliged to work?</p>
            <p>And is not the Advancement of their wages to 30 <hi>s. per month,</hi> in time of War, ſufficient, when in times of Peace, they are contented with much leſs?</p>
            <p>If theſe things be granted in the Affirmative, what reaſon have we then that theſe Grieveances ſhould not be redreſs'd? It is true, that the long continued courſe of an evil Cuſtom, whereby ſome particular Men may have made profit, will at firſt to them, ſeem grievous, and look like an Oppreſſion, but
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:47803:21"/>that is no reaſon at all why it ſhould not be removed, or why the Publick ſhould ſuffer by its continuance.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Object. 3.</hi> The War is now almoſt at an end, and we had better bear the Grievances a little longer, rather than charge our ſelves with any new Project now, that can be of little or no uſe to us in times of Peace.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſw.</hi> That the War is near at an end no Man knows, for we have ſo ſaid every year ſince it began, and, as we have thought, had reaſon ſo to ſay; but we ſee no end of it yet, nor know not when we ſhall; and whilſt it does continue, there are Grievances ſtill to bear, which may cauſe many an aking heart, and many a man to loſe his Life, which might be otherwiſe prevented, and did we but conſider the extraordinary Charge that the Nation, in ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral, is put to for want of a due Regulation, it would be motive ſufficient for every worthy Patriot and Lover of his Country, to ſeek out and help forward a Remedy to avoid it: for, abſtracting all the Complaints, Trouble, and Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſion that attends it, which is not a little, the very Charge alone that the King is at in Impreſſing, and the increaſe up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Merchants Wages, by the exorbitant Demands of Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, would in much leſs than one years time, make a Fund ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficient for the diſcharge of the Offices in this Regulation propoſed, for ever.</p>
            <p>The Charge of theſe Offices, by ſome general Tax, will not be felt, and without them, during any War, the Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Calamities will cry aloud and be heard. But the great<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſt Conſideration of all is the publick Safety of the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, which may well be preſumed to be in no ſecure and good Condition, without ſome more effectual Method for the breeding of Seamen and Manning the Fleet; and if the <hi>French</hi> had but been in a little ſtronger Condition 3 or 4 years ago.
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:47803:22"/>and but puſh'd on their War by Sea a little vigorouſly, it might have driven us to have thought of ſome more ef<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fectual method (tho perhaps then too late) or our Ruine.</p>
            <p>And to think that a Method or Regulation for Seamen, in time of Peace will be of no uſe, will be a miſtake; for per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>haps it may be then moſt neceſſary; I mean upon the proſpect of a War breaking out, for by this means, the Strength of the Nation, in reſpect to Seamen, may at any time be eaſily known and ſoon united, our Ships may be quick and earlier out, to the ſurpriſe and terror of our Enemies, and our Nation be happy and ſecure, our Merchants will not be tax'd by the Seamens extravagant demands, nor ſuffer for want of men in their Voyages, nor no ſuch things as Injuries, Complaints or Tears be heard of, occaſioned by the Rapines and Vio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lence of a Preſs.</p>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="31" facs="tcp:47803:22"/>
               <head>THE Practice and Uſe OF THIS METHOD In time of PEACE.</head>
               <p>Prop. 16. <hi>THAT in times of Peace, within Ten Days after Proclamation for that pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe to be made, all Penalties and For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feitures to ceaſe in the Regulation a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forementioned, until ſuch time as Proclamation ſhall be made again to the contrary, excepting all Penal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties in the fourth and ſixth Propoſals aforeſaid, the whole matter in them contained, being always to be obſerved both in times of Peace as well as War, and that the Maſters of all Merchant-Ships and Veſſels, be obliged to keep up in publick View, the Regiſter's Liſt, as in the twelfth Propoſal mentioned, and Forfeit the ſame Penalty upon Default.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="32" facs="tcp:47803:23"/>
                  <hi>Arg.</hi> 16. The Seamen being thus at all times obliged, as well in Peace as War, to enter themſelves in the Office, it will not only ſecure our Seamen, but their Numbers may at any time be known, and their Entry will be ſo fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miliar and eaſy to them, that in time of any enſuing War, there will be no ſtarting, but preſently fall into their old Methods, to the general Satisfaction of them all, finding that all ſhall have equal Fortune and Advantage, and that none can be oppreſs'd or endure more hardſhip than ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther: thus ſhall we have at all times our Seamen ready for the ſpeedy and effectual Manning of our Ships, to the Safety and Honour of our Nation.</p>
               <p>But I ſtill perceive there is one Objection more to an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer, which is ſomewhat material, that is, Where ſhall we find Money, when the Nation is already put to it to raiſe neceſſary Supplies for the War, to Pay and Maintain ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Charge that will be created by theſe Offices, and for the extraordinary Charge alſo of maintaining the Land<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men at the King's Yards, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>To this I anſwer, I ſhall not preſume to direct the Great Wiſdom of the Nation, but if there were no other way to raiſe this ſmall Tax, I would only propoſe one General Que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtion to the Merchants? Would they not be willing by ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving all their Grievances now remov'd, their Men to be kept free from Preſſing, whereby they might proſecute and finiſh their Voyages in Freedom, and to ſave ſuch conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derable Sums in their Wages? Would they not be contented for theſe Conſiderations, to pay 1 <hi>s. per</hi> Month more than the Rate fix'd for each Man in time of War, and 6 <hi>d. per</hi> Month in time of Peace to redeem them for the preſent, and to ſecure them for the future from ſuch Oppreſſions; and will they not otherwiſe, were no ſuch Regulation made, and the War continue, pay as much in one Year by the
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:47803:23"/>over-demands of Seamen, as will in all probability defray that Charge for twenty Years together, and it may be preſum'd that ſuch a Duty would ſufficiently defray the Charges propos'd; for in times of Peace there needs no continuance of raiſing and maintaining of Land<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, for Seamen will then breed faſt enough for our Oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſions.</p>
               <p>I Have thus humbly offered my Endeavours for the Publick Good, as well as my ſtrait Confinements, and want of Liberty, for further Inquiries would permit me. I ſhould not have preſumed to have Printed them, and by it have expos'd my Inabilities to the World, had I not been ſtrip'd by my late Loſs of that little all that I had, whereby I am made unable to pay for the Tranſcript of ſome few Copies, that I would willingly have preſented to ſome Perſons of Honor; with this humble Preſumption, only that if my honeſt, though defective Endeavours, may not in general be approv'd of; yet however, hoping that ſome little Light at leaſt may be given by it, whereby their Majeſties Fleet may be better ſerved, the Merchants relieved, and the Subjects in general be eaſed, which I cannot but think will be a very acceptable piece of Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice in our preſent Circumſtances of Affairs, and be well worthy of the Sollicitude and Endeavours of any Ingenu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous Lover of his Country. I cannot but be ſenſible of the difficulty that all new Projects have in their Birth, and that they are generally ſtarv'd in their Infancy with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out the Patronage and Protection of ſome Power. That mine deſerves but little regard I am ſatisfied in, nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther can my now unhappy and deſpicable Circumſtances recommend me.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="34" facs="tcp:47803:24"/>I have loſt the uſe of my Right Arm in the King's Service,<note n="*" place="margin">I loſt the uſe of my right Arm by a Shot I received in an Engage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment with a French Privateer in <hi>Jan. 1690.</hi> I was then Lieutenant under Captain <hi>John Layton</hi> in the <hi>Montague,</hi> who was kill'd in the beginning of that Action, his Head being taken off by a great Shot; and by my not giving due time for my Wound to be dreſs'd, and by Acting in my Poſt for above an Hour after, it had like to have coſt me my Life, the Surgeons often giving it for their Opinions, that I ſhould Die of my Wound.</note> and ſince that, have loſt all that I had in the World, when taken by the <hi>French,</hi> and I was carried into St. <hi>Maloes,</hi> and kept there a Priſoner near Five Months, and had not Almighty God in his particular Care and good Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vidence, in a wonderful man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner preſerved me there, I had been no longer the Object of any Perſon's fear or prejudice: but thanks be to God, who hath preſerved me thus far, and though he hath permit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted me to fall, and now to ſuffer under my heavy Sentence, I with Patience ſubmit to it, with this Comfort and Satiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>faction, that I never was reputed a Coward, and if I may truſt to my own Judgment of the late Action for which now I ſuffer, I think that I did my Duty to the utmoſt of my Power; and whereas it is a common ſaying after Miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fortunes, to cry out, <hi>If we had known before what would have come after, we could have prevented it, or have done better;</hi> it happens not ſo in my Caſe, for as God is my Witneſs, I know not how I could have done better, worſe for me it muſt have been, if I had acted otherwiſe than I did, for I was driven on the Edge of two Precipices, and if I had fallen either way, it would have been my inevi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>table Ruin, as may appear by my following Caſe, which I would not in any wiſe have Printed, had I not appeared in Publick in another Matter, and therefore I thought it very requiſite to take ſome notice of it, leaſt my Silence, as to this Matter, ſhould be imputed to my Guilt, which would have made me very uneaſy, for though I patiently ſubmit to my Sufferings, yet I cannot to my Guilt; I
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:47803:24"/>hope this will not be thought any Reflection at all upon that Honourable Court, that Try'd and Condemn'd me, for I cannot think that they acted contrary to their Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments in Condemning me, but do believe that they were led to it through the defect and weakneſs of my Defence, and the Teſtimony of ſome prejudic'd Witneſſes that were againſt me, which I cannot now particularly remember, but do believe that by my eagerneſs and endeavours to prove the ill Will, Prejudice and Combination of thoſe Perſons, I did neglect the more proper part of my Defence, that might otherwiſe have acquitted me, for the Truth of which, I appeal to the Honor and Judgment of all thoſe Honourable Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men who were my Judges, who no doubt will read or hear of this Writing. My Intention was to have ſaid as little as poſſible to my Caſe, that I might not tire the Reader, but going upon it, I found I could not do it in leſs room than as fellows, which I have taken Care to the very beſt of my Judgment and Memory, not to err one tittle from the Truth.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="case">
            <pb facs="tcp:47803:25"/>
            <pb n="37" facs="tcp:47803:25"/>
            <head>The CASE of Capt. <hi>JOHN PERRY,</hi> Lately ſentenced at a COURT-MARTIAL, For the LOSS of Their Majeſties FIRE-SHIP the <hi>Cygnett,</hi> to a <hi>Thouſand Pound</hi> Fine, and <hi>Ten Years</hi> Impriſonment.</head>
            <p>ON <hi>September</hi> the 20th. being about Twenty Leagues diſtance South-Weſt from <hi>Cape Clear,</hi> I then com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manding the <hi>Cygnett</hi> Fire-Ship, under the command of Captain <hi>Wickham</hi> of the <hi>Diamond,</hi> who was my Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modore, at Eight in the Morning the Wind at North-Weſt and by Weſt, we ſaw two ſail right to Windward, bear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing down upon us, I then made ſayl, and ſpoke with Captain <hi>Wickham,</hi> and told him, I believed they were French, and that I was getting my Ship in readineſs; he ſaid he believed the ſame, and directed me to lie under his Lee Quarter within call of him, and that if he would have me go upon Service, he would looſe his Spritſayl-Topſayl, and hoiſt it with the Sheets flying, according to
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:47803:26"/>the written Order, which I produced at my Tryal, and which he gave me ſome days before under his hand.</p>
            <p>About four Hours from our firſt ſeeing the Enemy, they came up with us, the <hi>Diamond</hi> being then under her Top-ſayl, and I (being a heavy Sayler) under my Top-fayls, with Foretack at Cathead, both ſteering away North-Eaſt and by North, one of the Privateers, called the <hi>Gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nado,</hi> firſt came up, and fired ſome Guns at the <hi>Diamond</hi> on her Weather ſide, whilſt the other, called the <hi>Philippo,</hi> came bearing down after her, with his Spritſayl Yard top'd, as I then believed, to board her, according to all Practice, on the Weather ſide; upon which I called to my Maſter, and told him, that I rerceived the Enemy was for board<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, and that I would be ſo too as ſoon as I had an op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portunity, although I had no Signal; whereupon he re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plied, If you pleaſe, we will get our Tacks on board, and be on board this Ship, which was then right to Windward of me; <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Muſquet ſhot, ſtanding towards the <hi>Diamond,</hi> as aforeſaid; and therefore I refuſed his inconſiderate Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion. Upon the coming up of the Privateer, the Diamond ſet her Fore fayl, with the Tack at Cathead, and let fall her Main ſayl, and ſtood away without altering her Courſe, when at the ſame time, he having the Wind of me, he might have bore down to me at any time, and eaſily have brought me to Windward, if he would have had me to have pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vented the Privateer from boarding him, as he hath ſince pretended, or have given me an opportunity to have burnt him. Seeing the <hi>Diamend</hi> thus to make fayl, and contrary to my firſt expectation, ſeeing the Privateer running up un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der her Stern, to board her on the Lee-quarter, on which ſide the lower tier of Guns was not out, I immediately ordered my Main and Foretacks, to be got on board, my Top ſayls to be hoiſted, and Mizzon to be hal'd abroad,
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:47803:26"/>and ſprung my Loof as near as I could lye, ſo to gain the Wind of the Privateer, that I might be ready to clap her on board, then believing, that by that time I could gain the Wind, the <hi>Diamond</hi> would have put off the Privateer, and that then I might have a fair opportunity of burning him, whilſt he lay becalm'd, or before he could have gathered way from under the <hi>Diamond</hi>'s Lee; but finding the <hi>Dia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mond</hi> did not put off the Privateer, as I and all Perſons pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent, every minute, expected ſhe would have done, I was then reſolved to burn him, notwithſtanding I had no Orders, as he lay with his Bough on board the <hi>Diamond</hi>'s Quarter; then believing, in that little time I had to conſider of it, that as ſoon as I had ſet fire to the Privateer, the Men, to ſave themſelves, muſt have run into the <hi>Diamond,</hi> and with ſuch haſte, that moſt of them muſt have gone without Arms, and conſequently have been forced to beg for quarter: This, as God is my Witneſs, was then my Thoughts and Reſolutions; but having gain'd the Wind, and brought the Privateer right a head of me, not half a Cables length diſtance, we ſaw the <hi>Diamond</hi>'s Colours ſtruck, and coming up very near, we perceiv'd none but French men upon the Deck, and no re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſtance made, and that the <hi>Diamond</hi> was loſt, I then found my Deſign ruin'd and prevented, and nor in my power to recover the <hi>Diamond,</hi> neither could I do any Injury to the Enemy, unleſs, at the ſame time, I had ſacrificed not only my ſelf, but all my Men, to the Revenge and Fury of the Enemy, we having no Ship nor Refuge left for us to hope to fly to, that could have ſaved us from the Purſuit and Deſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction of the other Privateer, who all the time, from the <hi>Phi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lippoes</hi> boarding the <hi>Diamond,</hi> was very near us, and ſiring upon us with both their great and ſmall Shot; and finding thus that we could do no ſervice, and that we had no power to eſcape or defend our ſelves, we ſurrender'd.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="40" facs="tcp:47803:27"/>But had I then burnt the Privateer, it is very probable as Cir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cumſtances ſince appear, it would have been my utter Ruine, though the Enemy had given me quarter; for my Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modore might have then ſaid, that I was the occaſion of the Loſs of his Ship, by telling that there was but a few Men boarded him, that they were at cloſe Quarters, the Enemy juſt ready to cry for Quarter, and that then I came without Orders or Notice, and fired the Privateer, put all his Men into a Conſternation and Dread of being burnt themſelves, fore'd all the Privateer's Men into the <hi>Diamond,</hi> who, by their greater Numbers, over power'd them, and ſo they loſt their Ship; and that if I had ſtaid till he had thought fit to give me the Signal, I might have done Service, and ſaved the Ship.</p>
            <p>All which, though Suppoſition only, I humbly offer to the Conſideration of the impartial Reader, and whether the World would not have eaſily believed ſuch an Allegation true, and that ſuch a Man of War could not have been otherwiſe loſt ſo ſoon, eſpecially to one Privateer.</p>
            <p>The Queſtion has been put, Why I did not burn my Ship, when I found I could not do Execution upon the Enemy? Whether it is thought a Fault in me, or no, I know not? But I humbly hope, that ſince there has been no Preſident of it, that ever I heard of, except it was when the Men could make their eſcape to ſhoar, or to a Fleet that could protect them, I ſhall not be thought a Crimi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal for it, it being very reaſonable to think, that had we deſtroyed our Ship when we were under their power, they would have prevented us from ſaving our ſelves on board any Merchant-ſhip, and have left us to the Mercy of the Sea, or deſtroyed us, which all my Men then ſaid, and I believed they would have done.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="41" facs="tcp:47803:27"/>This being the true and juſt account of my Caſe (as near as I can remember) what could have been more ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pected from me? I know not; it was my Unhappineſs to come home and be in this unfortunate Action, for which now I ſuffer: But if I had only lain in my Poſt for ſo ſhort a time as that wherein the <hi>Diamond</hi> was taken without making any Attempt at all (with Submiſſion to better Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments) I believe (<hi>If Orders are always to be obſerv'd</hi>) I might have juſtified my ſelf, though not ſo honourably, I being under Command, and to expect a Signal, which was never given me. But notwithſtanding that I did attempt to burn the Enemy, and had done it (thinking thereby to have merited the good Opinion of my Country) had I not to my great Surprize and Amazement found the <hi>Diamond</hi> ſo ſoon ſurrendred, which was immediately after ſhe was boarded.</p>
            <p>But the main and only Queſtion which I fail'd in anſwer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to at my Tryal, and for which the World generally condemns me, is, Why I did not burn the Privateer, or the <hi>Diamond</hi> and Privateer too, after I ſaw the <hi>Diamond</hi> was ſurrendred: All the Anſwer I made to it, when the Queſtion was put to me by the Court, was, That I believed, that if we had ſo done, we ſhould have had no Quarter, to which no Replication being made, threw me under that unhappy Miſtake, that they took my Anſwer for granted, believing, that if they had not ſo done, they would have ſignified it to me, and therefore I did offer no Reaſons, though pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>par'd to prove it, but did believe it needleſs, and indeed my Sentence, when given, was ſo unexpected and ſurpri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zing to me, that I thereupon replyed, That if the thing were to do again, I knew not how I could do any thing more or better than I did, and humbly prayed the Court to let me know wherein I had failed to do my Duty; but it was then too late, and I had no Anſwer to it.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="42" facs="tcp:47803:28"/>The Reaſons that I had then to offer were as followeth, Had it been poſſible for me to have burnt the Privateer and <hi>Diamond</hi> too, after ſhe was ſurrendred, thoſe on board the <hi>Diamond</hi> muſt have been burnt or drowned by their own Countrymen; but had we ſo done, it was impoſſible for us to eſcape, and as unreaſonable to expect any thing but utter Deſtruction from the other Privateer: This I did, and do ſtill believe would have been my Fate; and I muſt conſeſs it was the only thing that hindred me from attem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pting to do Execution after the ſurrender of the <hi>Diamond;</hi> and as I always did, and ever ſhall abhor deſerving the Name of a Coward, and my former Behaviour can never deſerve that Imputation, ſo on the other ſide, I would not throw my Life away, when there is not the leaſt proſpect of preſerving it.</p>
            <p>The Reaſons why I did, and do ſtill believe, that had we done Execution, and been taken, we ſhould have been de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nyed Quarter, is, in the firſt place, becauſe I knew it to be affirmed to be the Law of Arms and Nations, that Quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter was denyed to Fire-ſhips Men, if taken after Execution, in the Book <hi>De Jure Maritime &amp; Navali, lib.</hi> I. <hi>cap.</hi> 13<note n="†" place="margin">By the Laws of Nations, and by the Laws of Arms, and at this day practiſed, in all Fights, the ſmall Frigats, Ketches, and Smacks are to obſerve and take notice of the Enemies Fire-Ships, and to watch their motion, and to do their beſt to cut off their Boats, and gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rally <hi>the Perſons found in them are to be put to death, if taken, and the Veſſel, if not taken, deſtroyed;</hi> and the reaſon why the extremity of War is uſed to ſuch, is that by how much the Miſchief is the grea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter by the act of ſuch Men, if exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuted, by ſo much the Puniſhment is aggravated, if taken, and quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter denied them by the Law of War.</note>. the only Book that ever I heard of that treats of Sea-Affairs of that kind, and which has ben never writ againſt, or contradicted, that ever I heard of; but had there been no ſuch Law ever heard of, in my opinion (with Deference to better Judgments) the very Reaſon and Nature of the thing, in my Caſe eſpecial<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly might induce any Man to believe, that had I done Exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cution
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:47803:28"/>upon the Enemy, after the ſurrender of the <hi>Diamond,</hi> the utter Deſtruction both of my ſelf and Men might have been moſt juſtly expected; for what could have been more provoking and deſerving of Death, than for me, when the <hi>Diamond</hi> was loſt, and I under the Power of the Enemy (and they calling upon me to ſtrike) to do them the utmoſt Miſchief I could? Could I, in ſuch a caſe, expect or hope for quarter? A Garriſon that ſuffers a Storm, at the laſt extremity, has much more reaſon to expect it; for they may poſſibly ſave themſelves, but to us it was impoſſible; for when the <hi>Diamond</hi> was gone, there was nothing left to ſave us from the Power of the Enemy. Had not the other Priva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teer lain as he did firing upon us, and who had mann'd his Boats, and were coming to intercept and cut off our Eſcape to the Merchantmen (who were all upon the run as ſoon as they ſaw the <hi>Diamond</hi>'s Colours ſtruck, and) who ſail'd fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter than my Boat could row; even in that caſe no Merchant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man could ſave us or herſelf from the purſuit of the other Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vateer, who ſail'd very well.</p>
            <p>If ever there was any Preſident that was found contrary to the ſaid general Rule and Practice ſet down in the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid Book, of deſtroying Fireſhips men, if taken after Exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cution; and if there were any Men that ever had Quarter from the Enemy (which is more than ever I heard of) I preſume it muſt have been, not as in my Caſe, but when there was a probability for them to eſcape, when the At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempt was made. In general Fights Fire-ſhips are command<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed upon Execution, and muſt go, let their Fate be what it will, and then there is all probability for their Eſcape, a Frigat or Boats being always ready to take them up, and a Fleet able to protect them when taken up; but if they ſhould miſcarry, and are taken, the Enemy would have much more reaſon to forgive them, than for me, who could not plead either <hi>Command</hi> for <hi>Execution,</hi> or <hi>Hope</hi> of <hi>Eſcape</hi> after I had done it.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="44" facs="tcp:47803:29"/>All which I humbly offer to the charitable Conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions and Judgments of all judicious Perſons, and whether, if we had done execution upon the Enemy, after the ſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>render of the <hi>Diamond,</hi> we could have expected Quarter. I have been the more tedious upon this ſingle Point, becauſe I am generally condemn'd for it; and, I believe, had I ſpoke to it at my Tryal, it would have been now better for me.</p>
            <p>Upon the whole, I humbly hope it will be conſider'd, <hi>Firſt,</hi> That I was commanded to the Leeward of the <hi>Diamond,</hi> and as to my Diſtance, though it has been alledg'd againſt me by my Commodore, that I was not near enough to the <hi>Diamond</hi> to have prevented the Privateer from board<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing him, yet it can never enter into my Thoughts, that he did really think that I was not near enough to him, or that I could have prevented the Privateer from boarding him; for firſt, if he had not thought me near enough, he having the Wind of me, and Sailing much better than me, he might have boar down to me at any time, and brought me as near to him as he pleas'd: but if I had been ever ſo near to him, I know not how it could have been poſſible, or in my Power to have prevented the Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vateer from boarding, he having the Wind both of me and the <hi>Diamond</hi> too, and either of the Privateers could have run round me at any time, and have diſabled or ruined me at their pleaſure, I being unable to make any Defence, having ſent all my Men away as uſual on ſuch Occaſions, except my Boat's Crew, which row'd but with ſix Oars, my Ship was not only ſmall, but a very heavy Sailer, and being not fit for the Sea, was broak up at St. <hi>Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>loes</hi> whilſt I was there.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Secondly.</hi> That I was not at my own Liberty to act when I thought fit, for I was under a Commodore, who gave me Orders when I ſhould go upon Service, and whoſe Orders I was to obey.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="45" facs="tcp:47803:29"/>
               <hi>Thirdly.</hi> That he never did give me any ſignal for go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing upon Service during the Action.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Fourthly.</hi> That though I had no Orders, (and did run the hazard thereby of ruining my ſelf, if I had been un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſucceſsful in my Attempt) yet notwithſtanding, I did en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavour to do Service, and as it was ſworn at my Tryal, I did ſet all my Sails to gain the Wind, and that within a very little time from the Enemies boarding, I had gain'd the Wind, and had laid the Privateer on board, had the <hi>Diamond</hi> but held out, which ſhe might eaſily have done, had they but given the Enemy any reaſonable Op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſition at boarding, or at leaſt defended their Cloſe Quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters, or behaved themſelves any thing likely, which indeed, I did not in the leaſt ſuſpect when I was making my Attempt.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Fifthly.</hi> That if I could have done Execution after the <hi>Diamond</hi> was taken, yet it was impoſſible for me to eſcape.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Sixthly.</hi> If it was not unreaſonable for me to expect Quarter from the other Privateer, after I had burnt his Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fort or his Prize, knowing at the very ſame moment that I muſt fall under his Power.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Laſtly.</hi> If it can ſtill be thought, that I am in Fault, becauſe I did not do Service, though with the certainty of being denied Quarter, yet I on the other ſide with all ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion hope, that it may be conſider'd, that if I had hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pily been under the Command of a Man of War that had Fought any thing like what was reaſonably expected, I had not deſerv'd any Cenſure.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="46" facs="tcp:47803:30"/>I have given here as ſhort and brief Account of the Acti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on as I can, which relates to my particular Caſe, and have forbore perſonal Reflections as much as poſſible, without doing injuſtice to my ſelf, and have not omitted to the beſt of my Memory, any one material thing. There are indeed ſome other things which I hear have been reported to my Prejudice, and which I alſo think ſit here to take notice of and anſwer, by reaſon that I would not willingly remain any longer under any Perſons ill Opinion: one thing is, That the Maſter of my Ship would have had me attempted to have burnt the Privateer, before ſhe boarded the <hi>Diamond,</hi> and that I refuſed to do it, replying, that <hi>I was Captain of the Ship.</hi> This was indeed ſworn at my Tryal, and it was true that he did make ſuch a Motion, and I did refuſe it: and I ſubmit it to the Judgment of all thoſe Perſons who know the nature of Commands, whether any Captain is obli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged to act at any raſh or inconſiderate Motion of his Maſter, and whether the Maſters urging of it can be any excuſe for the Captain for any miſcarriage that may enſue by it. But without any other Arguments, ſuppoſing that I had had ever ſo fair and feaſible an opportunity to have burnt the Priva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teer; and in attempting it, without a Signal, had either been diſabled in my Maſt or ſunk, or after laying the Enemy on board, and ſetting fire to my Ship, ſhe had been put off a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain (which indeed very commonly happens, tho men of War be diſabled,) would not then the whole Miſcarriage and Loſs of the Action have been fix'd on me, and could my Maſter's advice have then excuſed me for acting without Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders, when I was under Command and to expect a Signal, and might not then my Commodore have alledged, that by my Misbehaviour in acting without Orders, I had both en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>couraged the Enemy, and diſcouraged the <hi>Diamond</hi>'s Men, crying out, that <hi>their Fire-ſhip was gone,</hi> &amp;c. and that if I
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:47803:30"/>had ſtaid till he had ſeen time, I might not only have ſaved his Ship, but have done execution on the Enemy.</p>
            <p>Another thing has been objected, that I wanted Powder, and that my Sally-Ports were not open to ſhew that I was a Fire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip; as to my want of Powder, I did ſend to the <hi>Diamond</hi> for ſome, (tho not on purpoſe) but 'twas ſome conſiderable time before the Enemy came up with us, my Fire-works being a little dammaged by ſome bad Weather we had received ſome few days before; but it not being ſent, I ſtarted ſome Cartridges, which I was unwilling ſhould o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therwiſe have been done, and my Ship was very well ſit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted for Service, long before the Enemy came up, as my Gun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner ſwore at my Tryal; and as to the not opening my Sally-Ports, I kept them ſhut to preſerve my Priming dry, till ſuch time as I ſhould have occaſion to open them, upon quitting my Ship, in doing execution. But had I not had that reaſon, I ſhould have thought it beſt to have kept them ſhut, to have conceal'd the Quality of my Ship, for the greater ſecurity of ſervice; and not, by diſcovering my ſelf, to have bid the Ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>my, (who were both to the windward of me, and ſa led two foot for my one) to have avoided, diſabled or ſunk me: for I did not expect, nor I dare ſay did any other Perſon then pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent, upon the coming up of thoſe Privateers, that they would have took the <hi>Diamond,</hi> or that there was any occaſion for our Frighting them, for then certainly my Commodore would have opened all his own Ports, and have had all his Guns out, and have tack'd and ſtood to the Enemy, and have alſo or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dered me to have kept my Ports open.</p>
            <p>I ſhall be no farther tedious to the Reader, only in all Humility to beg and hope that the publication of my Caſe will not give any Offence, or be thought a Crime, but ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther that my <hi>unhappy Circumſtances</hi> may be commiſerated that hath given any occaſion for it. The heavy and black Clouds of Inſamy, that like Death have hung over me, have made
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:47803:31"/>my Life very uncomfortable, and I had rather not <hi>live,</hi> than <hi>live contemptible,</hi> and my Reputation being as <hi>dear</hi> and <hi>tender</hi> to me as my <hi>Life,</hi> I could not ſee it bleeding and at it's utmoſt extremity, without giving it this Relief, eſpecially having ſo fair an Opportunity; and indeed, the late Wounds <hi>in it</hi> have ſtruck <hi>ſo deep,</hi> that it has made me often wiſh, that my <hi>Life</hi> and <hi>that,</hi> had gone together, but God Almighty, who in his great Goodneſs, ſees what is beſt and fitteſt for us, will I hope, in his good Time, deliver me out of all my Troubles: in the mean time, I humbly hope, that I ſhall have the kind Reader's charitable Thoughts, which to me will be like viſiting the Diſtreſſed in Priſon, for which every Perſon has undoubtedly a good Security of Reward.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed, and are to be Sold by <hi>John Whitlock</hi> near <hi>Stationers-Hall,</hi> 1695.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:47803:31"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
